<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Soldering PCB Components Task :: DIY-AT</title>
    <link>https://diy-at.andreaspolydorides.com/makers-workshop/soldering/index.html</link>
    <description>This task will require you to hand-solder a number of components onto a PCB, simulating the process of building a design called LoopOne.&#xA;LoopOne LoopOne is an open-source design that aims to alleviate thermal discomfort among wheelchair users. It works by circulating water through a tube in the wheelchair’s cushion for a cooling or heating effect which the user can control as required. In addition to improving the user’s comfort, thermally regulating the seat temperature can minimise the risk of pressure sores.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://diy-at.andreaspolydorides.com/makers-workshop/soldering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A refresher (or lesson!) on soldering</title>
      <link>https://diy-at.andreaspolydorides.com/makers-workshop/soldering/soldering-learning/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://diy-at.andreaspolydorides.com/makers-workshop/soldering/soldering-learning/index.html</guid>
      <description>Tools and Parts Needed: Soldering iron Soldering wire Tip cleaner Flux Tinner Prototyping board Red cable Black cable Learning Task Instructions: Assemble the tools and components needed for this task Identify the prototyping board (shown below) Affix the cable given to you through the prototyping board Apply some flux and use the soldering iron and wire to solder the cable to the board Power off the iron, securely set aside and check the connection, here’s a useful image by Adafruit that can help you judge the quality of your solder joints.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soldering the PCB</title>
      <link>https://diy-at.andreaspolydorides.com/makers-workshop/soldering/soldering-task/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://diy-at.andreaspolydorides.com/makers-workshop/soldering/soldering-task/index.html</guid>
      <description>Have you done the required reading? It’s here&#xA;Tools and Parts Needed: Soldering Iron Soldering Wire Tip Cleaner Flux Tinner PCB Screw Terminal (black, 2-pin) Inductor (grey cylinder, 2-pin) JST-XH connectors Soldering helper (choose from 3D printed jig, masking tape, or “helping hands”) Soldering Task Instructions: Assemble the tools and components needed for soldering Prepare PCB for soldering with soldering setup of choice. Affix the screw terminal on the PCB with a “helping hand” or with some masking tape. Be mindful of its orientation. Note If you are using the 3D printed soldering jig, you want to start with the shortest component we will be soldering today, the JST-XH connectors. Verify the orientation and solder the component to the PCB. Now try to solder more components.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>